Thartchaieni Singam

Stockholm, Sweden

+46700326253

thartchaieni@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a passionate UI designer with a holistic approach, merging user-centered and business-driven strategies to create user-friendly designs aligned with business goals. Committed to high accessibility standards, I believe in technology's inclusivity, aiming for seamless digital experiences for all.

EXPERIENCE

UI Specialist, 05/2024 - 12/2024

ParlayBay - Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

UI Designer, 11/2021 - 03/2024

The Mobile Life - Stockholm, Stockholm County, Sweden

- Spearheaded the conceptualization and execution of innovative design solutions, ensuring a harmonious blend of aesthetics and functionality.
- Conducted thorough user research and leveraged feedback to inform design decisions, resulting in intuitive and enjoyable user experiences across diverse industries.
- Collaborated closely with diverse teams to translate business goals into compelling design solutions that exceed user expectations.

UX Designer, 08/2021 - 10/2021

Minna. - Stockholm, Stockholm County, Sweden

Designer& Product Development, 01/2015 - 06/2017

XFYRE Advanced Defence & Security Technology - Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Design wearable bulletproof garment
- Research new fabrications, techniques, tooling and materials
- Develop prototypes based on my designs
- Detailed tech packs and complete development of product drawings to final sample
- Sourcing trims and fabrics, ordering raw materials and communicating with vendors

Assistant Designer, 08/2013 - 06/2014

On Aura Tout Vu - Maison Haute Couture - Paris Area, France

- In the design team with all aspects of creating and executing the seasonal collections
- Perform research to help inspire upcoming collections

Menswear Designer/Product Developer&Merchandiser, 11/2011 - 06/2013

Poolman Textilhandels GmbH - Dietzenbach, Hessen, Germany

- Developing and presenting fashion-focused products
- Working closely with senior designers and technical team
- Involved overseas trip to source new fashion trends, ideas and concepts for menswear
- Detailed tech packs and complete development of product from initial drawings to final sample

SKILLS

- Figma
- User-centred design
- Cross-Functional Collaboration
- Responsive Design
- Design Tokens and Systems
- Rapid Prototyping
- Mobile ux design proficiency
- HTML and css basic knowledge
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Information architecture
- Framer

EDUCATION

 $\textbf{Certificate of Higher Education}: \mathsf{UX}/\mathsf{UI}$

Design, 12/2020

CareerFoundry - Berlin. Germany

Bachelor's Degree: Fashion studies,

12/2011

Paris American academy - Paris, France

Intensive Degree Course: Business / Economy / Language, 12/2008

Feng Chia University - Taichung, Taiwan

WEBSITES

- www.linkedin.com/in/thartchaieni
- https://chaieni-singamportfolio.framer.website/

Student Internship, 09/2009 - 10/2009

ELIE SAAB - Paris Area, France

- During Paris Fashion Week 2009
- Made sure all pieces were returned to clothes rack in order
- Helping assistant designer with garments fitting for fashion show preparation
- · Assist with backstage model board

ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND AWARDS

- Achievement: Issued by Musée National de Monaco · Jan 2011-Contributed designs/sculpture for Exposition à Monaco: On Aura Tout Vu modernises les Poupées GALEA.
- **Award:** Issued by Fashion One Television · Jun 2014 Design Genius Season 2- Runner up

AWARDS

- Design Genius Season 2
- Levi's Jeans competition

LANGUAGES

Tamil, Malay: First La	inguage		
English:	C1	Chinese:	В1
Advanced		Intermediate	
French:	A2		
Elementary			